well that was our tool chain from last week
这是我们上周的工具链
this week is different javascript
这周是不一样的的 javascript
let me just put this
让我把它放一下
i have a three production already
我已经有三个产品已经
just named after me, four
以我的名字命名了, 哦，是四个
my job is to keep our code running
我的工作是保持我们的代码运行
while other packages are changing theirs
而其他软件包正在改变他们的代码。
should you learn javascript nope
你应该学习javascript吗 不应该
is there any other option ? no
有没有其他选择？ 没有
oh look another library was added today to patch
看， 今天又增加了一个库
the problems of the other 150 that were also released
以修补其他150个已发布库的问题
did you know javascript
你知道javascript
was actually written in seven days
实际上是在 7 天内编写的
such a messy language i love it
这样一种混乱的语言，我喜欢它
did you know javascript was actually not written in seven days
你知道javascript实际上不是用七天写成的吗
no one ever knows what value
没有人知道，变量是什么值，
variable is or what its type is,  now we use typescript
或者它的类型是什么, 现在我们在用typescript
we still don't know
我们仍然不知道
i'd rather use rust or webassembly
我宁愿使用rust或webassembly
they say adoption is coming
他们说 adoption 就要来了
they said that 10 years ago
他们10年前就这么说了
they say that every year but this year is different
他们每年都这么说 但今年不同
is it scalable no
是否具有可扩展性 没有
is it maintainable no is it portable
是否可以维护 不行 是否具有可移植性
not really yeah we use react we actually
并非如此 我们用 React 我们实际上
use pre-act we actually use svelte
用 Preact 我们实际上使用 svelte
we actually went back to vanilla javascript
我们实际上回到了原生 javascript
yeah we're using a library for this that
是的，我们为此使用了一个库，
we rewrote to vanilla javascript
我们将其重写为 原生 javascript
because it wasn't efficient we're stuck with
因为它效率不高，我们被
this messy language
这种混乱的语言困住了
now i love it javascript yeah
现在我喜欢它 javascript 是的，
it's the  defacto standard do you know there's a
这是事实上的标准，你知道有一个
library for that i wouldn't trust the
库可以做那个吗 我应该不相信的
let's say finance application with
假设财务应用程序使用
javascript what our finance application
javascript 我们的财务应用程序
does is totally fine to use javascript
所做的事情完全可以使用 javascript
but i'd recommend using typescript not that we do
但我建议使用 typescript 而不是我们所做的那样
we had callback hell
我们有回调地狱
and then we went to promises
然后我们转向了promises
await came out went back to promises and now we
await来了 然后我们回到了promises 现在我们
rewrote everything back to callbacks
重写了所有的东西回到了回调
because it's just more comfortable
因为它只是更舒服
at least you know it's bad
至少你知道它不怎么样
oh it's probably just a quick fix
oh 它可能只是一个quick fix
will take me three to five days to find it
我们尝试了三到五天才找到它
we tried coffeescript rewrote our codebase
我们尝试了coffeescript 重写了我们的代码库
try typescript rewrote our codebase and then
我们尝试了typescript 重写了我们的代码库
we went back to vanilla javascript
然后我们回到了原生 javascript
because it's just more comfortable so we
因为它只是更舒服，所以我们
rewrote our codebase again yeah we used
重写了我们的代码库再次使用
react and then react 16.8 came out and
react 然后 react 16.8 出来了，
we had to rewrite everything to hooks
我们必须用 hooks 重写
react 17 came out we had to rewrite everything again
react 17 出来了，我们不得不再次重写所有内容
and then react script
然后 react script
was updated to version 0.4
脚本更新到版本 0.4
and we had to fix everything
我们必须修复一大堆东西
to work with local images and
来使用本地图像，现在
now react version 18 is coming out
react 18 出来了
we'll rewrite everything again we rewrote our code base
我们不得不再次重写所有内容，我们重写了我们的代码库
around nine times this month yeah
约有九次，这个月
you can use redux totally fine but but
你可以使用 redux 完全没问题，但
if you're on it i'd recommend you use
如果你在使用它，我建议你使用
redux toolkit but actually it's better
redux toolkit 但实际上
to use flux or flumax or flexible
最好使用flux或flumax或灵活
actually better to use recall not that
实际上更好地使用recall，而不是
we do but now react came out with the
我们这样做，但现在 react 带有
hooks and context api which apparently
hooks 和 context api，这显然
is better than redux apparently we'll
比 redux 更好，显然我们会
rewrite everything again sometimes it
再次重写所有内容，有时它
just doesn't transpire we usually
只是不会发生我们通常
rewrite our code base now we actually
重写我们的代码库现在我们实际上
wrote a custom transpirer to transpile
编写了一个自定义的 transpirer 来 transpile
transpider it's such a messy language we
transpider 它是如此混乱的语言 我们
use it for our website desktop app
将它用于我们的网站桌面应用
mobile app for the fridge the tesla is
程序用于冰箱的移动应用程序特斯拉
not actually native i mean it is
实际上并不是原生的我的意思是它
actually native but it's sort of not
实际上是原生的但它不是
really native it's sort of hybrid native
真正的原生它是一种混合原生
but some of it is native i mean some
但所以 我是原生的，我的意思是有些
people use it in a native way
人以原生方式使用它，
but we don't really use it in a native
但我们并没有真正以原生方式使用它，从
way technically a lot of people are
技术上讲，很多人正在
switching back to native no one has
切换回原生，没有人
switched yet angular
切换
talk to me when you use angular 2 or
过，但当你使用 Angular 时，请与我交谈 2 或
react npm is such a bad package manager
react npm 是一个糟糕的包管理器，
no one uses that anymore npm is such a
没有人再使用它 npm 是一个
good package manager how many languages
很好的包管理器，有多少种语言
have one so that major version breaks
有一个，所以主要版本破坏
our code but our code breaks the minor
了我们的代码，但我们的代码破坏了次要
version i still don't know how to fix
版本，我仍然不知道如何修复
pure dependencies until this day
直到今天，纯依赖关系
yarn bpnpn turbo would make sense right
yarn bpnpn turbo 才有意义，对
javascript doesn't think so jquery what
javascript 不这么认为
are you five
we use jj query global variables
no one uses them it must be somewhere in
the window how do you debug node apps
you don't you just write good code but
你只是写了好代码，但
not in javascript no one ever masters
不是在 javascript 中没有人掌握
javascript i get a hundred thousand
javascript 我
points in stack overflow i'm still a
在堆栈溢出中获得了 10 万分 我仍然是一个
noob node is technically multi-threaded
菜鸟节点在技术上是多线程的
javascript is technically performant our
javascript 在技术上是高性能的 我们的
code
代码
is never safe when they'll blow up
在它们爆炸时永远不会安全
probably won't work anymore probably
可能不再起作用 可能
will be using rust or webassembly or
会使用 rust 或 webassembly 或
whatever j s an array is technically
任何 js 数组在技术上
just an object object or object null is
只是一个对象对象或对象 null 在
technically not an object but objects
技术上不是一个对象，但对象
can be known so they technically can be
可以是已知的，因此它们在技术上可以
non-object unless they're an object
是非对象，除非它们是 对象是
right so technically null is an object
对的，所以从技术上讲 null 是一个对象，
yes
是的
it's a bit hacky i admit
，我承认它有点 hacky，
but javascript is by design is it easy
但是 javascript 是设计使然，它很
to learn
容易学习
have you tried javascript probably will
你是否尝试过 javascript 可能
be a bit hacky have you used javascript
会有点 hacky 你
before i don't recommend i don't like
在我不推荐之前使用过 javascript 我不喜欢
our tool chain documentation
我们的工具链文档
and another advantage is that it's free
和另一个优点是它是
so was java before it was bought by
免费的，Java 在被 oracle 购买之前也是免费的，
oracle
so we prepare ourselves by installing
所以我们通过
modules from npm then we compile it to
从 npm 安装模块来准备自己，然后我们将其编译为
typescript then we use a term spyler
typescript，然后我们使用一个名为 bubble 的术语 spyler
called bubble to transpile it to es5
将其转换为 es5
load it with system.js file for
加载它 使用 system.js 破产文件将
bankruptcy bundle it all up with webpack
它与 webpack 捆绑在一起
use it in a framework like react and let
，在诸如 react 之类的框架中使用它，并
the state be managed by redux or flux
让状态由 redux 或
flummox or flexible or recoil or
Flummox 或灵活或反冲或
whatever js and voila
任何 js 管理，
all of this just to avoid using jquery
瞧 所有这些只是为了避免使用 jquery
or in our case jj query but that'll be
或在我们的例子中是 jj 查询，但这
probably less performant
可能会降低性能，
as most of the things this isn't our
因为大多数事情这不是我们的
production code it will be tomorrow
生产代码，明天
though probably gonna get fired again
可能会再次被解雇，
i mean there's really no alternative to
我的意思是真的别无选择
javascript right now de facto no one
现在到 javascript 实际上没有人
really knows what the value is until we
真正知道价值是什么，直到我们
get an error
得到一个错误
i love it well try writing anything
我很喜欢它现在尝试在
without javascript nowadays javascript i
没有 javascript 的情况下编写任何东西 javascript 我
love it
喜欢它
no i don't recommend it
不，我不推荐它